Chris (クリス) BOURGEONNIER

9 1

Tokyo, JAPAN (Residency: HCMC - VIETNAM)



+ 84 (0) 909 619 511 (Line, Signal, Viber)



chrisbourgeonnier@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/chrisbourgeonnier



github.com/chrisbourgeonnier





FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

After 16 years in Vietnam, I have decided to relocate to Japan and transition into web development, aiming to take advantage of my experience to make a difference. My diverse professional background has given me the ability to think out of the box, and communicate complex ideas in simple terms, making me an effective team player. I am passionate about creating functional applications to solve real-world problems, and I always look forward to new challenges and opportunities to learn and grow.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby On Rails HTML / CSS Heroku
Git/GitHub Bootstrap Figma

PostgreSQL JavaScript ES6 Adobe Suite

Stimulus.js React CAD & 3D Modeling

LANGUAGES

English: Native Level **Japanese:** Currently learning (N5)

French: Native Language Spanish, Vietnamese: Basic Knowledge

HOBBIES

DIY, home improvement Motorsports and sim racing

EDUCATION

2023 Full Stack Web Developer | Batch #1388

₹ Tokyo (JP)

9-week full-time intensive coding bootcamp - Le Wagon

2022 BA (Hons) Interior Architecture and Design

♀ London (UK)

First Class Honours - University of Hertfordshire

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MY PORTFOLIO

chrisbourgeonnier.me



Basho - www.basho-app.me

A web app to create, edit and curate your favorite places, visited or yet to visit. Role: Full-Stack Developer and pitcher in a team of 4 members.

- Designed, implemented and shipped to production in 2 weeks.
- Presented the app on Demo Day, with an audience of over 120 people.

// Rails, Stimulus.js, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Figma // API: MapBox, Geocoder, Google



Git link

HeroHub - herohub-tokyo-b8670f0c5306.herokuapp.com

A C2C website which allows users to get in touch and book super-hero services.

- Designed, implemented and shipped to production - 2 weeks, team of 4 members. // Rails, Stimulus.js, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Heroku // API: superheroapi.com

DESIGN EXPERIENCE

2022 / 11 Interior Designer: 1-Month Internship

💡 Tokyo (JP)

Suzuko Yamada Architects (https://suzukoyamada.com)

- Physical model making: Thinking process, experimentation and building of 2 projects: a 200sq.m open office and a 45sq.m house
- Introduced the basics of TwinMotion 3D viz. software to the team.

- Transformed a 50m2 office space, designing new floor plans and a 3D model
- Designed the brand identity for exterior façade and signage, interior, uniform and business cards (Quang Nang Trading Company)
- Supervised the project execution.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2007 - 2021 English Teacher: Universities, Colleges, Schools and Centers

→ HCMC (VN)

HCMC International University & University of Law (VASS branches), University of

Economics and Finance, College of Education, LFI Duras

- Taught Business and General English, all levels; Focus on communication skills
- Taught English and STEM
- Prepared 1,000+ students for Cambridge, TOEIC, TOEFL, IELTS exams.
- Trained over 300 Vietnamese students to become English teacher

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

2008 - 2011 Director – PariSaigon Café - Restaurant

PHCMC (VN)

- Founded and designed a French-style Café Restaurant.
- Organized various events (art exhibitions, gaming parties, themed evenings)
- Managed a team of 10 employees

Chris (クリス) BOURGEONNIER

9

Tokyo, JAPAN (Residency: HCMC - VIETNAM)



+ 84 (0) 909 619 511 (Line, Signal, Viber)



chrisbourgeonnier@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/chrisbourgeonnier



github.com/chrisbourgeonnier





FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

Driven by a passion for technology, and a keen interest for programming, I have recently transitioned into web development, aiming to take advantage of my experience to make a impact. My diverse professional background has given me the ability to think out of the box, and communicate complex ideas in simple terms, making me an effective team player. I am passionate about creating beautiful and functional applications to solve real-world problems, and I always look forward to new challenges and opportunities to learn and grow.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby On Rails HTML / CSS Heroku
Git/GitHub Bootstrap Figma

PostgreSQL JavaScript ES6 Adobe Suite

Stimulus.js React CAD & 3D Modeling

LANGUAGES

English: Native Level Japanese: Currently learning (N5)

French: Native Language Spanish, Vietnamese: Basic Knowledge

HOBBIES

DIY, home improvement Motorsports and sim racing

EDUCATION

2022 BA (Hons) Interior Architecture and Design
First Class Honours - University of Hertfordshire

♀ London (UK)

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MY PORTFOLIO

chrisbourgeonnier.me



Basho - www.basho-app.me

A web app to create, edit and curate your favorite places, visited or yet to visit. Role: Full-Stack Developer and pitcher in a team of 4 members.

- Designed, implemented and shipped to production in 2 weeks.
- Presented the app on Demo Day, with an audience of over 120 people.

// Rails, Stimulus.js, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Figma // API: MapBox, Geocoder, Google



HeroHub - herohub-tokyo-b8670f0c5306.herokuapp.com

A C2C website which allows users to get in touch and book super-hero services.

- Designed, implemented and shipped to production - 2 weeks, team of 4 members. // Rails, Stimulus.js, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Heroku // API: superheroapi.com

DESIGN EXPERIENCE

2022 / 11 Interior Designer: 1-Month Internship

Tokyo (JP)

Suzuko Yamada Architects (https://suzukoyamada.com)

- Physical model making: Thinking process, experimentation and building of 2 projects: a 200sq.m open office and a 45sq.m house
- Introduced the basics of TwinMotion 3D viz. software to the team.

2022 Interior Designer, Graphic Designer : Freelance Work

- PHCMC (VN)
- Transformed a 50m2 office space, designing new floor plans and a 3D model
- Designed the brand identity for exterior façade and signage, interior, uniform and business cards (Quang Nang Trading Company)
- Supervised the project execution.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2007 - 2021 English Teacher: Universities, Colleges, Schools and Centers

→ HCMC (VN)

HCMC International University & University of Law (VASS branches), University of

Economics and Finance, College of Education, LFI Duras

- Taught Business and General English, all levels; Focus on communication skills
- Taught English and STEM
- Prepared 1,000+ students for Cambridge, TOEIC, TOEFL, IELTS exams.
- Trained over 300 Vietnamese students to become English teacher

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2008 - 2011 Director – PariSaigon Café - Restaurant

PHCMC (VN)

- Founded and designed a French-style Café Restaurant.
- Organized various events (art exhibitions, gaming parties, themed evenings)
- Managed a team of 10 employees